Martin Gichuri Ndungu

Kenyan | 3593+p5v Kigali | +250 790801109 gichurindungu@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Skype ID cd8dab2d741f4610

SUMMARY

Martin Ndungu is a Mastercard Foundation scholar at the African Leadership University, pursuing studies in software engineering and entrepreneurship. He is fueled by his passion for social innovation, especially through technology. Martin aims to build on his academic foundations in software engineering and entrepreneurship through continued school work and part-time professional development. His quest for knowledge and value for a positive work ethic has contributed immensely to his recent success at One Step Education Consultants (CA) as a research assistant. Here, he has helped conduct and manage research projects within Kenya. Meanwhile, he is aiming to understand the practical nuances of data analytics for social development through a part-time internship in a data science field, non-profit organization, or a social enterprise.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Name of University - Kigali, Rwanda

January 2022 - present

BSc (Hons) Software engineering

Relevant Coursework: Entrepreneurial leadership, stakeholder management, entrepreneurial research, human-centered design, Python programming, web development (Node.js, html, css) web server management.

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant January 2021 – present

One step education consultants – Toronto, Canada

- Conducting and managing research projects to identify opportunities for students and tutors
- Facilitating recruitment and training of new research assistants in Kenya
- Reviewing research projects to suit client specifications.

Project manager June 2020 –November 2020

County Government of Nyandarua – Nyandarua, Kenya

- Drafted proposals for youth-led initiatives across Nyandarua county
- Secured over \$1000 in funding for youth groups in the region
- Managed teams of over 40 to oversee road works and construction projects sanctioned by the county government.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Volunteer, Nyandarua County Government coronavirus sensitization program

March 2020 - May 2020

Distributed over 500 liters of homemade sanitizers to families across Nyandarua

Helped raise the awareness of coronavirus

volunteer, Touch a Child's Heart (TACH)

May, 2016 – November 2018

Supported the expansion of NGO across schools in Nyeri

Facilitated high school collaborative campaigns for the Global Mater heart run

Spearheaded events to encourage networking amongst street children enrolled in the programs

Coordinated the development of child feeding programs in primary schools in Nyeri County Kenya

Volunteer, St Mary's child rescue center

February 2015- December 2018

Tutored young students enrolled in the Program

Raised \$500 for the center's initiation campaign during the 2018 day of the African child

Helped co-ordinate the collection and distribution of community donations for the program

SKILLS

- Meticulous researcher
- Articulate writer

- Skilled public speaker
- Excellent tutor for peer groups

INTERESTS

Data science and analytics

• Artificial intelligence

Agribusiness

Photography

 Communication for impact (podcasts)

LANGUAGES

- English- professional proficiency
- Gikuyu
- Swahili– professional proficiency